{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Jungle Book","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatle Boot","The Lion King","The Little Mermaid"],"question":"In Which Disney Movie Were There Characters Called \"John, Paul, George & Ringo\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"1982","incorrectAnswers":["1988","1990","1977"],"question":"In Which Year Did Kraftwerk Achieve Their First UK No.1?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portugese ","incorrectAnswers":["English","French","Italian"],"question":"What Nationality Was Vasco Da Gama?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Adam Clayton Plays Bass Guitar For Which Band?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","The USA","France"],"question":"Which country administers Christmas Island?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Military strategist","incorrectAnswers":["Botanist","Artist","Astronomer"],"question":"Who was Sun Tzu?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Three","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Yellow","Eight"],"question":"In German, what is the meaning of the word 'drei'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"An exaltation","incorrectAnswers":["A run","A gaggle","A nest"],"question":"What is the word for a group of larks?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Salem","incorrectAnswers":["Sabrina","Coven","Providence"],"question":"In Which American Town Did The 1692 Witchcraft Trials Take Place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Sudan","Syria","Tunisia"],"question":"What country borders Libya on the East?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bertrand Russell","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Spinoza","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Science is what you know. Philosophy is what you don't know'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1969","incorrectAnswers":["1948","1955","1962"],"question":"In which year did the first human set foot on the moon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bone","incorrectAnswers":["Musical Instrument","Joinery","Painting Techniques"],"question":"Ulna, radius, and clavicle are types of __________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jerusalem","incorrectAnswers":["Baghdad","Tel Aviv","Bethlehem"],"question":"Which city is sacred to Jews, Christians, and Muslims?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Buenos Aires ","incorrectAnswers":["Sao Paolo","Mendoza","Cordoba"],"question":"Name the capital of Argentina.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Pixies","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Marley and The Wailers","Otis Redding","Joni Mitchell"],"question":"Which artist first recorded 'Where Is My Mind', which was later covered by Tkay Maidza?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Spirit of St Louis","incorrectAnswers":["Heart of Houston","Body of Baltimore","Soul of Seattle"],"question":"What was the name of Charles Lindbergh's plane in which he completed the first non-stop solo trans-Atlantic flight?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ceylon ","incorrectAnswers":["Kipur","East Pakistan","Mirar"],"question":"What was Sri Lanka Previously Known As?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Soar","A Queen","A Worker"],"question":"What is a female hamster known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Claret ","incorrectAnswers":["Burgundy","Shiraz","Cabernet Sauvignon"],"question":"What name was given to the light, clear wine developed in medieval times along the coastal valleys of the Gironde river in the Bordeaux region?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Kurt Vonnegut","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Edgar Allan Poe","Stanisław Lem"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Slaughterhouse-Five'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The voice box","incorrectAnswers":["Books","Ancient laws","The history of speech"],"question":"What is Laryngology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tampa Bay Rays","incorrectAnswers":["Tamba Bay Trailblazers","Tampa Bay Bengals","Tampa Bay Pistons"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Tampa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Luxembourg","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Liberia","Laos"],"question":"Which country is the northernmost among Luxembourg, Liechtenstein, Laos and Liberia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Salat","incorrectAnswers":["Ramadan","Sunna","Hijab"],"question":"What is the second pillar of Islam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Boo Radleys","incorrectAnswers":["The Smiths","Deep Purple","Pink Floyd"],"question":"Which British alternative band takes its name from a character from To Kill a Mockingbird ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Uni","incorrectAnswers":["Ika","Ebi","Ahi"],"question":"What is the name of the Japanese food made from the gonads of sea urchins?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Dissertation","incorrectAnswers":["A Writ","A Treatise","An Epilogue"],"question":"What is the name for a research paper that is written as a final requirement for a doctoral degree?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kiss","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","The Pussycat Dolls","Mötley Crüe"],"question":"Gene Simmons is a member of which band?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","Iran","Iraq"],"question":"In which country did the Kemalists oppose the Sultan and eventually prevail in the 1920s?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Philip of Macedon","incorrectAnswers":["Julius Caesar","Alexander the Old","Marc Anthony"],"question":"Who was the father of Alexander the Great?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The pen is mightier than the sword","incorrectAnswers":["Be still and know","For the good","With hard work, all things increase and grow"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Calamus gladio fortior'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Calcium carbonate","incorrectAnswers":["Calcium sulphate dihydrate","Iron Oxide","Deuterium Oxide"],"question":"What chemical has the formula CaCO3?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Baton Rouge ","incorrectAnswers":["New Orleans","Des Moines","Louisville"],"question":"What is the state capital of Louisiana?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Aldous Huxley","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Robert Louis Stevenson","Arthur Conan Doyle"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Brave New World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"German","incorrectAnswers":["English","Russian","French"],"question":"In what language was the Communist Manifesto written?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Renegade\" by Styx","incorrectAnswers":["\"Circle of Life\" by Elton John","\"I'll Make a Man Out of You\" by Donny Osmond","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Oh, Mama, I’m in fear for my life from the long arm of the law...\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"First person","incorrectAnswers":["Second person","Third person","Plural"],"question":"In language, 'me' is which type of pronoun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"George Lucas","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Star Wars: Episode II – Attack of the Clones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1967","incorrectAnswers":["1973","1979","1985"],"question":"When was the first heart transplant?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Basketball","Soccer","Tennis"],"question":"\"The Perfect Game\" is a 2009 family movie about which sport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"3","incorrectAnswers":["2","4","5"],"question":"How Many Movements Traditionally Make Up A Concerto?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Steven Spielberg","incorrectAnswers":["Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese","Alfred Hitchcock"],"question":"Which director directed Schindler's List?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Thank you","incorrectAnswers":["Hello","Yes","Goodbye"],"question":"What does the French word 'merci' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aston Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Toyota","Austin","Volkswagen"],"question":"Which car manufacturer made the DB5?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Lesser Lion","incorrectAnswers":["Iron Lion","Ferocious Lion","Brave Lion"],"question":"What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Leo Minor ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Kareem Abdul-Jabbar","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Jordan","Yao Ming","Kobe Bryant"],"question":"Who was the NBA's most valuable player in 1976, 1977 and 1980?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Yohji Yamamoto","incorrectAnswers":["Miu Miu","Dior","Felix Malikovich"],"question":"Which of the following fashion designers is famous for their use of the color black?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Tonga is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"John Logie Baird","incorrectAnswers":["Karl Benz","Johannes Gutenberg","Eli Whitney"],"question":"Who First Demonstrated Television In 1926?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Hobbit","incorrectAnswers":["Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","Bluebeard","Jonathan Livingston Seagull"],"question":"In which book does 'Thorin' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"7","incorrectAnswers":["8","6","9"],"question":"How many sides does a heptagon have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Peter Paul Rubens","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Rothko","Vincent van Gogh","‎Rembrandt van Rijn"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Massacre of the Innocents\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jitterbug","incorrectAnswers":["The Twist","The Charleston","The Salsa"],"question":"Which popular dance is mentioned in the Wham! song 'Wake Me Up Before You Go-Go'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soju","incorrectAnswers":["Canelazo","Rakı","Tuba"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Korea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Silk Road","incorrectAnswers":["The Spice Route","The Tea Route","The Coffee Round"],"question":"What was the name of the famous trade route that was established in the 2nd century BCE?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Elvis","incorrectAnswers":["John Lennon","Bob Marley","Freddie Mercury"],"question":"Which singer made $55 million between October 2013 and 2014 despite being dead since 1977?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bobsy-die","incorrectAnswers":["Groke","Whippersnapper","Tittynope"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a great deal of fuss or trouble'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Cubism","Surrealism","Romanticism"],"question":"Which school of painting focused on transitory visual impressions with an emphasis on the changing effects of light and color?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Keaton","incorrectAnswers":["Christian Bale","George Clooney","Val Kilmer"],"question":"Who played the title role in the 1989 film \"Batman\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1954","incorrectAnswers":["1958","1962","1966"],"question":"In What Year Did The Vietnam War Begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A former neo-nazi tries to prevent his brother from going down the same path that he did.","incorrectAnswers":["King Arthur and his Knights embark on a search for a religious relic.","An undercover cop and a mole in the police try to identify each other while infiltrating a gang.","A Scottish warrior leads his countrymen in a rebellion to free his homeland."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie American History X?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Port Moresby","incorrectAnswers":["Luanda","Paramaribo","Bangui"],"question":"What is the capital city of Papua New Guinea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Culture Club","Dire Straits"],"question":"Which English-Australian pop group released the album 'Horizontal'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Odense","incorrectAnswers":["Barcelona","Oslo","Helsinki"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Denmark?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tomato","incorrectAnswers":["Garlic","Onion","Chili Pepper"],"question":"What Is Alicante A Variety Of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nineteen Eighty-Four","incorrectAnswers":["The Man in the High Castle","Blindness","Brave New World"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"London","incorrectAnswers":["Paris","Dublin","Brussels"],"question":"Where is Westminster Abbey located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The World According to Garp","incorrectAnswers":["Lonesome Dove","The Sun Also Rises","The Age of Innocence"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'T. S. Garp'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kuwait City","incorrectAnswers":["Abu Dhabi","Doha","Amman"],"question":"What is the capital of Kuwait?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Nepal","Sri Lanka","Bhutan"],"question":"Which country in Asia was formerly part of British India? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ireland ","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Denmark","Finland"],"question":"Which country does one associate with 'Barmbrack'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cricket","incorrectAnswers":["Motor Racing","Gymnastics","Basketball"],"question":"With which sport is Sir Gary Sobers associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hamlet","incorrectAnswers":["Macbeth","Juliette","King Lear"],"question":"Which Shakespearean Character has the most lines in a single play?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jet Li","incorrectAnswers":["Kenneth Branagh","Luke Evans","Stephen Fry"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including The Expendables and The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Drake","incorrectAnswers":["A Boar","A Jack","A Stallion"],"question":"What is a male duck known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Van Gogh","incorrectAnswers":["Salvador Dali","Andy Warhol","Raphael"],"question":"Which painter reputedly cut off his own ear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Gibberish","incorrectAnswers":["Gobbledygook","Blatherskite","Flummox"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'unintelligible or meaningless speech'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Black","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Hungary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Baroque","incorrectAnswers":["Impressionism","Surrealism","Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"Beheading of Saint John the Baptist\" by Caravaggio is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Quartz","incorrectAnswers":["Hematite","Borax","Epsom salt"],"question":"What is silicon dioxide commonly known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Haloo Helsinki!","incorrectAnswers":["Nightwish","Stratovarius","Sonata Arctica"],"question":"Which Finnish rock music group released the album 'III (edition 1)'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A Nanny","incorrectAnswers":["A Billy","A Gertie","A Hattie"],"question":"What Is A Female Goat Called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Flamenco","incorrectAnswers":["Tap","Hip-hop","Waltz"],"question":"What style of dance does Solero de Jerez hold the world record for 16 heel taps per second?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Calcium sulphate dihydrate","incorrectAnswers":["Silicon dioxide","Iron Oxide","Isopropyl alcohol"],"question":"What chemical compound makes gypsum?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thomas Hobbes","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig Wittgenstein","Friedrich Nietzsche","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The life of man (in a state of nature) is solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"In the beginning","incorrectAnswers":["Praise the lord","Let there be","Hallelujah! Hallelujah! Hallelujah!"],"question":"What are the first three words of The Bible?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United Arab Emirates","incorrectAnswers":["Eritrea","Israel","Djibouti"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Saudi Arabia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Twice the speed of sound","incorrectAnswers":["Twice the speed of light","200 miles per hour","2 miles per second"],"question":"If you were travelling at mach 2 how fast would you be travelling?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jodie Foster","incorrectAnswers":["Frances Fisher","Rachel Weisz","Salma Hayek"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Taxi Driver and Contact?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Tonalpohualli","incorrectAnswers":["The Tenochtitlan","The Olmec","The Mixtec"],"question":"What is the name of the Aztec calendar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Dravidian","Japonic"],"question":"The language 'Amharic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anthony Hopkins","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Douglas","Bill Murray","John Belushi"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Hannibal Lecter in The Silence of the Lambs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Damascus","incorrectAnswers":["Mogadishu","Islamabad","Bamako"],"question":"What is the capital city of Syria?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Krypton","incorrectAnswers":["Argon","Helium","Xenon"],"question":"In 1898, which noble gas was discovered and named after the Greek word for 'hidden'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Meryl Streep","incorrectAnswers":["Julie Andrews","Jessica Lange","Sissy Spacek"],"question":"Who won the 1982 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Sophie in Sophie's Choice?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Bulgaria","Libya"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Meteora?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Two horizontal bands of red and white. The red band contains a white crescent and stars.","incorrectAnswers":["Red with a blue cross outlined in white that extends to the edges.","Green, with large white script and a sword.","Three equal vertical bands of orange white and green."],"question":"What does the flag of Singapore look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Chevrolet","Toyota","Honda"],"question":"Which car manufacturer offered the Torino and the Tempo?","difficulty":"medium"},